（小関(おぜき)）ンンッ…
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）
やっぱり ここじゃったか
I figured you'd be here.
（小関）あっ…　潮(うしお)
Ushio.
No trace left of it, huh?
（火ノ丸）きれいさっぱり
なくなっちまったのぅ
Yeah.
（火ノ丸）
名を 潮火ノ丸といいます
My name is Ushio Hinomaru.
In order to reach yokozuna,
the highest rank in sumo,
のちに 大相撲の最高位
横綱へ至る道として—
I must become the strongest
high school sumo wrestler!
高校相撲の頂点を
取らんとする者じゃ！
ウヘヘッ…　懐かしいのぅ
Good times.
It all started here.
こっから始まったんだもんな
あんときゃ １人じゃった相撲部が
２人になって…
The sumo club went from one member to two,
and now, we have six guys
aiming to be the best in Japan.
今じゃ ６人　日本一を目指しとる
Honestly, I'm a little scared.
（小関）俺 正直 怖いよ
（火ノ丸）うん？
３年の俺は 負けたら今日で引退だ
I'm a third-year, so if we
lose today, that's it for me.
But...
でも…
I don't want my journey to end yet.
まだ終わりになんてしたくない
I want to keep sumo wrestling
with everyone in the club.
もっと このメンバーで
相撲を取っていたい
（小関）
フフフッ…　また弱気なことを…
I'm whining again.
I'm a pathetic excuse for an upperclassman.
相変わらず 俺は
情けない先輩のままだ
（火ノ丸）どんなにコケにされても
たったひとりで守り続けた相撲部
You kept the sumo club going,
even when others made fun of you.
If you hadn't done that,
none of us would be here now.
部長がいなけりゃ ワシも誰も—
こうして集まることはなかった
You're not pathetic at all.
情けなくなんかねえ
部長が守った ここがあるから
今のダチ高相撲部がある
The Dachi High sumo club
only exists because of you.
今日で引退なんか させねえよ
We won't let today's bouts be your last.
We're gonna breeze through the
prefectural prelims and go to nationals!
まずは県予選　そして 全国！
You're coming with us all the way to the top.
つきあってもらうぜ
てっぺんまで！
Right!
Bout 7
"The Honest Clown"
National High School
Sumo Championships
Chiba Prefectural
Preliminary Bouts
Pledge!
（金盛(かなもり)）宣誓！
Each sumo wrestler here trains to cultivate
their spirit, technique, and body.
（金盛）我々 選手一同は—
日ごろの修練で培った心･技･体(しん   ぎ   たい)を
存分に発揮し—
Inside this ring measuring
4.55 meters in diameter,
直径4,55メートルの円の中—
力の限り 戦い抜くことを誓います
we shall fight to the very
best of our abilities!
So declares Kanamori Tsuyoshi,
the wrestlers' spokesman!
（金盛）選手代表 金盛剛(つよし)
（橋）こっちッス 礼奈(れいな)さん
This way, Reina-san.
Hey!
（西郷）お〜い
（礼奈）なに？　これ
What's all this?
Everyone looks super pumped for this.
すごい盛り上がってんじゃん
We will now begin the fifth match
in round one of the tournament.
（アナウンス）
これより トーナメント１回戦
第５試合を始めます
（寺原(てらはら)）お〜い 火ノ丸
応援しに来てやったぞ！
Hey, Hinomaru! We're here to cheer you on!
（殴る音）
いてっ！　アアッ…
We're here incognito, remember.
（柴木山(しばきやま)）
今日は お忍びで来てるからね
I don't want us to stand out.
あまり目立ちたくないの
（寺原）
十分 目立ってると思いますよ
You stand out like a sore
thumb all by yourself.
First in the ring, on the west side,
from Odachi High School: Ushio-kun.
（アナウンス）
先鋒戦(せんぽうせん)　西 大太刀(おおだち)高校 潮君
On the east side, from Kashiwa
Technical High School: Ito-kun.
東 柏(かしわ)実業高校 伊東(いとう)君
Odachi High School? Never heard of 'em.
（男性１）
大太刀高校？　聞いたことないな
Kashiwa Tech is a real powerhouse,
and they've made it to nationals before.
（男性２）柏実業っていったら
全国出たこともある強豪だぜ
And look at the difference in physique.
It's obvious who'll win.
（男性１）
しかも あの体格差 決まりだろう？
Hands on the ground.
（審判）手をついて
（礼奈）ンッ…
（審判）はっきよい！
Spirit!
Hinomaru was too slow to react?
（寺原）火ノ丸が立ち遅れた？
（柴木山）いいや
No.
That kid... He used Saenoyama-zeki's charge.
あいつ 冴ノ山関(さえのやまぜき)の立ち合いを…
ウワッ！
Arm
Arm Grab
Arm grab underhand throw!
Arm Grab Un
Arm Grab Under
Arm Grab Underhand
Arm Grab Underhand Thr
Arm Grab Underhand Throw
Demon
Wheel
Demon Wheel Rear Attack!
Demon
Wheel
Rear
Attack
Demon
Wheel
Rear
Attack
All right!
（小関）よし！
（蛍(けい)）やった！
He won!
Incredible!
（礼奈）すごい！
He can throw someone from that stance?
（西郷）
あの体勢からでも投げれんのか
フゥ…
（桐仁(きりひと)）さて 鬼丸(おにまる)先生が
景気よく決めてくれたところで—
Okay, now that Onimaru-sensei
has shown what he can do,
how about we show everyone
引き続き 教えてやりますか
what the dark horse, Dachi High,
is capable of?
皆さんの知らないダチ高ってやつを
（小関たち）おう！
Yeah!
Could that short-ass be the kid
もしかして あの小さいの—
この間 大和国(やまとくに)の息子と
いい勝負したっていう…
who gave Yamatokuni's son
a run for his money?
You serious?
マジかよ？　あいつが あの…
That's the guy?
National treasure, Onimaru Kunitsuna.
（金盛）
国宝 鬼丸国綱(くにつな)か　確かに強いな
He looks pretty strong.
Make sure you get to the finals.
（沙田(さだ)）
勝ち上がってきなよ 決勝まで
おい　どこへ行く？
Hey, where are you going?
This magazine wants to interview me.
雑誌のインタビューがあるんで
じゃ！
So see ya!
生意気な…
That cocky jackass.
（荒木(あらき)）オッ…　次は あいつだ
Oh, he's up next.
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
Chihiro Special #13!
Chihiro
Special
#13
Chihiro
Special
#13
Chihiro
Special
#13
外無双(そとむそう)！　レスリングとの共通技か
An outer thigh propping twist down.
That's used in wrestling, too.
See? I told you Chiharu was interesting.
ねっ？　面白いっしょ？　チハル
Is he the guy you met
while you were suspended?
（真田(さなだ)）
お前が謹慎中に会ったってヤツだな
Jeez, we don't need our secret weapon
going around introducing himself.
…たく　秘密兵器が
自己紹介に行くなってんだよ
（佑真(ゆうま)）おら！
Chaotic thrusts!
（佑真）乱突き･開手(かいしゅ)！
（選手）ウウッ…
（男性１）おお〜！
（男性２）すげえ回転数だ！
His hits are really fast!
Screw this. I'm backing off.
くそ！　だったら 退(ひ)いて…
（桐仁）押して退くのと
押されて退くのは まるで違う
Backing off when you're being hit is very
different to backing off when you're on top.
グハッ！
Yuma!
佑真！
Yuma-san, you're so cool!
（西郷たち）
佑真さん　かっけえッス！
ほう…
So he wasn't just messing around.
遊んでいたわけじゃなさそうだな
Odachi High School's pretty strong!
大太刀高校って強(つえ)えじゃん！
They've won three bouts in a row,
so they're already into the second round!
無傷の３連勝で ２回戦進出だ！
From what we've seen so far, their other
two team members must be incredible!
この分だと あとの２人も
すごいのが控えてんじゃねえ？
Huh?
（２人）あれ？
You did fine.
それでいい　今は こらえろ
Stay strong.
I see now.
なるほどね
ダチ高は 先に強えヤツを置いて
逃げきる作戦か
They put their strongest guys in first.
Just look at their captain.
だって 大将なんて見てよ あれ
完全にビビってんじゃないスか？
ありゃ いじめられる顔だね
He looks absolutely terrified.
He looks like a bully's plaything.
Just watch. These final bouts
are what I'm most interested in.
いいから よく見てろ
俺は むしろ
この大将戦を見に来たんだからよ
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
（柴木山）ほほう…
R-Railroaded?
（荒木）で… 電車道！
きっかけさえあれば化けるのさ
あの手のヤツは
Given the chance, someone
like that can transform.
And the person who gave him that chance...
そのきっかけを与えたのが—
...is Dachi High's sixth member:
Tsuji Kirihito.
ダチ高の６人目 辻(つじ)桐仁
Dachi High is no longer
Onimaru's one-man team.
（金盛）ダチ高は
もう鬼丸のワンマンチームじゃねえ
We'll go all out against them!
総力戦でいくぞ！
Hinomaru, Ishi High's watching us.
火ノ丸　石(いし)高が見てるぜ
Yeah.
（千比路）
もう俺たちと当たる気でいやがる
They're already gearing up to fight us.
Fine by me.
望むところじゃ　決勝で待っとれ！
We'll see them in the finals.
Oh, there he is.
あ〜 いたいた　潮君
Ushio-kun!
Sada Mizuki.
（火ノ丸）
土俵の上で向かい合うまでは—
I wasn't planning on meeting you
until we engaged in combat in the ring.
顔を合わせたくなかったんじゃが
Oh, don't be like that.
（沙田）まあまあ そう言わないで
You've got your semifinal match next.
次 準決勝なんでしょう？
Breeze through it so we can have our fight, 'kay?
サクッと勝って
早く俺とやろうよ！
随分 楽しそうじゃのぅ
You seem excited by the prospect.
Of course I am!
そりゃそうだよ
Middle school sumo was
so boring without a rival.
ライバルのいない中学相撲は
ホントつまんなかったから
I must thank you for making it this far,
national treasure, Onimaru Kunitsuna.
ここまで這(は)い上がってくれたこと
感謝するよ
国宝 鬼丸国綱
You have nothing to thank me for,
Mikazuki Munechika.
感謝される筋合いはねえよ
三日月宗近(みかづきむねちか)
I'll have to get dirt on your blade.
その刀身に 土 つけさせてもらうぜ
Match over. Dachi High,
on the west side, wins 4-1.
（アナウンス）以上
４対１で 西 大太刀高校の勝ち
Yeah!
（佑真）しゃ！
（小関）決勝進出だ！
We're in the final round!
They won!
やった やったぁ！
But that scrawny guy
spells trouble for them.
（舟木）しかし
あのチビ１人が足引っ張ってんな
He's the only one with
losses across the board.
（橋）これまでの試合
黒星は全部 あいつだ
He's weak, but he still
charges straight at them.
（礼奈）
弱いくせに真っ向勝負だなんて…
Even if you want to be like him...
いくら あいつに
憧れてるからって…
To put it simply, Ishigami High
School's team this year is strong.
（桐仁）はっきり言って
今年の石神(いしがみ)高校は強い
Probably the strongest they've ever had.
歴代最強と言っていいだろう
We could make a tactical call and
put Mitsuhashi in against Sada.
戦略として 沙田に
三ツ橋(みつはし)を当てるという手はある
沙田からの勝ちは捨て
ほかで確実に勝ち星を取る
Give Sada an easy win, and focus
instead on winning the other bouts.
Still, there's no perfect plan against
a nationally ranked opponent.
だが
どのみち 全国レベルを相手に—
確実に勝つ方法なんて
ありはしない
We need every win we can get.
捨てていい勝負なんてねえんだ
We'll face them head on and win.
This is but a pitstop on our journey.
がっぷり四つで ねじ伏せるぞ
ここは通過点だ
Let's go become the best in Japan!
行こう 日本一へ！
（一同）おう！
Yeah!
This is the final round
of the team competition.
（アナウンス）団体戦 決勝…
On the west side: Odachi High School.
西 大太刀高校　先鋒 三ツ橋蛍
First in the ring is Mitsuhashi Kei.
Going second is Kunisaki Chihiro.
二陣 國崎(くにさき)千比路　中堅 五條(ごじょう)佑真
Going third is Gojo Yuma.
副将 小関信也(しんや)
Going fourth is Ozeki Shinya.
東 石神高校　先鋒 間宮圭一(まみやけいいち)
On the east side: Ishigami High School.
First in the ring is Mamiya Keiichi.
Going second is Araki Gennosuke.
二陣 荒木源之助(げんのすけ)　中堅 金盛剛
Going third is Kanamori Tsuyoshi.
Going fourth is Sanada Yuki.
副将 真田勇気(ゆうき)
The fifth and final fighters
are Ushio Hinomaru
大将 潮火ノ丸
and Sada Mizuki.
大将 沙田美月
Bow.
（審判）礼！
（一同）お願いします！
Let's have a good match!
First in the ring, on the
west side, Mitsuhashi-kun.
（アナウンス）先鋒戦 西 三ツ橋君
（蛍）はい
Here!
On the east side, Mamiya-kun.
（アナウンス）東 間宮君
あ〜あ…　こんなの
やる前から結果は見えてるよ
Wow, you can already see
how this is gonna play out.
（男性２）体重差100キロ以上
下手すりゃ死ぬぞ
He must weigh 100 kilos more than him.
He might even die here.
It's impressive that an amateur with
his physique can charge the way he does.
あの体格で 素人が—
真っ正面からぶつかっていけるのは
すごいんスけどね
But two months' training just isn't enough.
２か月で仕上げるには
時間がなさすぎたか
Dachi High is basically a team of four.
ダチ高は 実質
４人で戦ってるようなもんですよ
It's true that losing any bout
at this stage is a setback.
確かに
この戦いにおける１敗は重い
But...
ただ 三ツ橋君の顔は
勝負を捨てた顔ではない
Mitsuhashi-kun's expression tells me
he hasn't thrown in the towel.
And his teammates don't look like
they're the only four trying.
送り出した部員たちも ４人で
戦っているつもりは なさそうだ
（蛍）グハッ！
クッ…　もういっちょう
One more time.
You've got guts, charging
in head-on like that.
（桐仁）大したもんだよ
頭から突っ込む そのガッツはさ
If you've got something
to say, please say it.
言いたいことがあるなら
言ってください
Nothing you say will make me feel worse.
今更 何言われても
傷つきゃしませんよ
（桐仁）
お前は本当に よくやってるよ
You're doing really well.
But at this rate, you won't be
ready for the Inter High prelims.
ただ このままでは
インターハイ予選には間に合わない
Hey, you need to put your hands on the ground.
（審判）君　早く手をついて
（蛍）オ… オス
Yes, sir.
フッ…　何だ？　ありゃ
What's he doing?
He must've got that from watching Onimaru.
（間宮）
恐らく 鬼丸の影響だろうな
He's always charging head-on, too.
（間宮）あくまで正面突破…
いじらしいことだ
It's touching, in a way.
（金盛）間宮！
（間宮）うん？
Mamiya!
Show everyone...
（桐仁）見せてやれ お前の覚悟を
how serious you are!
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
He disappeared!
（間宮）消え…
Wh-Where'd he go?!
ど… どこだ？
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
He disappeared!
（間宮）消え…
Wh-Where'd he go?!
ど… どこだ？
（柴木山）うん？
（寺原）八艘(はっそう)飛び！
A leaping charge!
He didn't come up with that
on the spur of the moment!
思いつきでできる動きじゃない
稽古のたまものだ
It must be something he practiced.
A change?
（蛍）変化 …ですか？
（桐仁）ああ　作戦としては有効だ
Yeah, it's a solid strategy,
but I didn't want to suggest it,
でも 火ノ丸に…
真っ向勝負に憧れてるお前に—
because I know how much you
respect Hinomaru's head-on charge.
俺は
そんなことを勧めたくないんだ
There's no point doing sumo if
you don't like how you're doing it.
自分の理想を曲げてまで
相撲を取る意味はないだろう
You still have two more
years to look forward to.
来年 再来年を見据えて…
How I'd like to do sumo?
（蛍）僕の理想って何ですか？
（桐仁）うん？
Hinomaru-san has worked very hard
to wrestle the way he does now.
（蛍）火ノ丸さんが
今のスタイルを貫くのに—
どれだけ頑張ってきたか…
I could never waltz up, casually imitate him,
and go, "My bad, I lost."
それを今の僕が
軽々しくマネをして—
“はい 負けました”なんて
言えますか？
Especially not if it happens to be
in the finals of a team tournament.
ましてや
それが団体戦の決勝だとしたら…
Next year and the year after aren't enough!
来年 再来年じゃダメなんですよ
I'm nothing but a burden,
どう見ても 足手まといの僕を—
but Hinomaru-san and the captain smile
at me and make me feel welcome.
火ノ丸さんや部長は
笑って受け入れてくれた
Even Gojo-san and Kunisaki-san,
五條さんや國崎さんだって—
who could've led someone
stronger if they felt like it...
その気になれば 僕より強い人を
引っ張ってこれたはずなのに…
Coach, please show me how I can win.
監督　教えてください！
ここ一番で勝てる方法を
本当に必要なときに
みんなの役に立てるなら—
If I can help the team out when it counts,
I'll do it even if it isn't
what I want or respect!
憧れも理想も
捨てる覚悟はできている！
If you had made this change earlier,
（桐仁）最初から
この変化を使っていれば—
you might have scored some
victories in earlier rounds.
決勝までに
何勝かは挙げられたかもしれない
But that isn't your end goal.
だが お前が欲しいのは
そんなもんじゃない
The reason you kept losing so nobly
目先の勝利さえも捨てて
玉砕を続けたのは—
is because anyone at your size would be
expected to have tricks up their sleeve,
お前の体格では どうしても
相手の頭によぎる変化に対し—
and you played the honest clown
to make them lower their guard.
愚直な道化を演じることで
その警戒を解くため
You did it so this move would work
when it mattered most
ここ一番での成功率を上げるため
and help us beat Ishi High!
（桐仁）石高に勝つために！
（間宮）ンンッ…
（桐仁）三ツ橋　勝て！
Mitsuhashi, win it!
Go!
（火ノ丸たち）いけ〜！
No way!
（蛍）そんな…
（千比路）反応が速すぎる！
He reacted too quickly!
He was expecting it?!
読まれてた？
I figured they had some sort of plan.
（金盛）やはり何か仕込んでたか
If our captain hadn't warned me,
I'd have been in trouble.
（間宮）主将のひと言がなければ
危なかった
諦めるな！　手を伸ばせ！
Don't give up!
Keep reaching!
Dammit!
（桐仁）くそ！
Well, he couldn't do much more.
（舟木）まあ しかたないよな
順当な結果だ
It's a fair result.
But... that was awesome. He's incredible!
（西郷）
けど あいつ すげえな　すげえよ！
（荒木）ロクに
スポーツ経験もないんだろう？
You've never played a
sport before, have you?
It seems pretty arrogant for you to
expect to win if you just use your brain.
そんなヤツが策を弄して
勝とうとすること自体がさ
おこがましいと思わねえ？
（千比路）ンンッ…
（小関）國崎…
Kunisaki!
Nice!
（桐仁）いいぞ！
Once you're behind him,
it doesn't matter if he's bigger!
後ろにつけば 体格差も関係ねえ
一気に攻めろ！
Just push!
But it's the kind of trick you
can't use more than a few times.
しかし これ
何度も使える戦法じゃねえぜ
That's why we'll save it for Ishi High.
だから
石高戦まで取っておくんですよ
Wait, you think you've got
a chance against Ishi High?
（千比路）何だ？　お前
石高相手に勝つつもりだったのか？
安心しろ　誰も
お前が勝つなんて期待してねえから
Don't worry.
No one's expecting you to win.
The captain and Gojo
are improving by the day.
（千比路）今は 部長も五條も
いい感じに伸びてるしな
お前は お前で
個人戦のつもりで 気楽にやんな
You can just treat it like
it's an individual competition.
（蛍）僕だけ 思い出作りに
行くわけじゃないんですよ
I'm not going just to make
some happy memories.
僕だって 日本一を
目指すチームの一員なんだ！
I'm on this team to
become the best in Japan!
見てろ
Just watch.
Someday, you'll be really thankful when I win!
いつか 僕の勝利に
感謝するときが来るからな！
Mitsuhashi!
（小関）三ツ橋
す… すみません
I-I'm sorry.
何言ってんだ　よく頑張ったよ
What are you talking about? You did great.
（千比路）
…たく　跳び過ぎなんだよ
Man, you jumped too far.
You got too nervous in the clutch.
ここ一番で力みやがって
Even if he was expecting it, you should've
gotten yourself in a better position.
読まれたにしたって もう少し
いい体勢 作れたはずだろう？
（小関）お… おい 國崎
（蛍）クッ…
H-Hey, Kunisaki...
Man, what am I gonna do with you?
（千比路）…たく しょうがねえな
You'd better make me thankful
during nationals.
全国では 俺に感謝させてみせろよ
I see. So this is what makes
a team competition what it is.
（千比路）なるほど
これが本当の意味での団体戦か
Yo, Chiharu.
よう チハル
This is the first time I've wanted to win
for someone other than myself.
初めてだぜ 自分以外のために
勝とうと思ったのは
On the west side: Kunisaki-kun.
There's a lot riding on this second bout.
（橋）この二陣戦は注目だな
（西郷）ああ
Yeah.
On the east side: Araki-kun.
It's the wrestling champion
versus the judo champion.
レスリング王者 対 柔道王者の
異種格闘技戦
A combat sports showdown!
この間のケリをつけようか
ゲンゴロウ
Time to settle our score, Gengoro.
源之助だ！
しかし できるもんなら—
It's Gennosuke.
But if I'd had my way, I would've preferred
facing you in an individual competition.
あんたとは
個人戦で当たりたかったよ
This will be Dachi High's second loss.
あんたが負けたら
ダチ高は２敗目だ　あとがない
You'll be toast.
But that pressure to do well for
the team only constrains our fight.
でも そんなプレッシャーは
勝負において しがらみでしかない
しがらみ？
Constrains?
そういう不純物は
全て取っ払って決めてえんだ
I want to have a duel that's
free of such impurities
so we can find out who is stronger.
どっちが強えのか
（荒木）団体戦っつっても
結局は 個人戦×(かける)５
It's called a team competition,
but it's really five individual bouts.
Let's not go nuts over this one.
気負わず 勝負に没頭しようぜ
Oh, I get it.
なるほどな　お前は
そぎ落として強くなるタイプか
You're the type who gets stronger
by casting aside anything unnecessary.
Don't worry. I'm always at my best, Mutsugoro!
安心しろ
俺は いつだって
ベストテンションだ　ムツゴロウ
That's not even close to my name!
もはや ひと文字も合ってねえ！
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
Huh?
（男性）えっ あれ？
（ざわめき）
They're not moving.
（男性）ヘヘッ…　なに？　あれ
（男性）おいおい おいおい…
（男性）見合い過ぎだろう
見合って見合って…
（男性）おいおいおい　どうした？
Hey, engage already!
（男性１）おい 組み合えよ！
（男性２）これは相撲だぞ！
This is boring!
（男性）組み合えよ！
The crowd's turning ugly.
すっげえヤジ
まあ 純粋に相撲が見たくて
来てる客もいるからね
A lot of the spectators
are just here to see sumo.
These two have honed techniques
in different disciplines.
それぞれ別競技で培い
洗練してきた技を持つ者同士
That's why they don't
want to attack recklessly.
だからこそ
うかつには踏み込めない
They know they're at their most
vulnerable when they get in close.
互いに 組み際が
いちばん危険なことを知っている
But I think the first to move will be...
だが 先に動くのは恐らく…
Kunisaki's attacking!
（舟木）國崎から行った！
A double leg takedown!
（小関）双手(もろて)刈り！
（桐仁）よし！
Good!
It's harder to counter
lower attacks with judo!
（桐仁）柔道という競技は
下半身への攻撃に弱い
I figured you'd try that.
（荒木）
…とでも思ったかよ？　ナメるな
Don't underestimate me!
どの格闘技が最強か
…なんて議論はナンセンスだね
Arguing which discipline
is stronger is nonsensical.
俺がチハルに勝ったところで—
When I beat Chiharu,
レスリングより柔道が
強えなんてことにはならねえ
it won't mean that judo is
stronger than wrestling!
If you're strong, you're good at
everything you turn your hand to.
強えヤツは
何してようが強えんだよ
But that's neither here nor there right now.
そんなことも 今は どうでもいい
The crowd's cheers and jeers...
観衆の声援もブーイングも
柔道王者の肩書も—
The title of judo champion...
先輩らの思いも
つらい稽古に費やした日々も—
The expectations of my upperclassmen,
the days I spent training...
今は全て雑念だ
Those are all worldly distractions!
Cast them aside!
そぎ落とせ！
“目の前の相手に勝利する”
それ以外の全てを！
The only thing that matters is
defeating the opponent in front of you!
Countering with an inner thigh throw?
（千比路）
カウンターの内股だと！？
Kunisaki!
（小関）國崎！
Cast it aside, huh?
（千比路）“そぎ落とす”か…
I used to be like that,
obsessed with my own strength.
俺も 今までは自分の強さにしか
興味がない男だった
But...
けどな…
They're already under my skin.
もう焼き付いちまって
そぎ落とせねえんだ！
I can never cast them aside!
He's countering with a hip throw!
（舟木）腰投げで返した！
For the past month, I've been strengthening
my feet, making them more dexterous.
（千比路）この１か月で
徹底的に鍛えた足裏の感覚
土をつかむ筋力
Now, they can grip the ground!
もらった！
I win!
（柴木山）あっ…
（寺原）空中で切り返した？
A front flip in midair?
But he's off-balance!
だが 体勢は よくない
たたみかけろ！
Pressure him!
A sweeping grab!
（間宮）払い巻き込み！
（真田）柔道の捨て身技だ
That's a judo sacrifice throw!
C-Crap, he's pulling me
down with all his weight.
マ… マズイ
全体重で持ってかれる
None of my wrestling moves
will help me out of this one!
俺のレスリングじゃ
ここから挽回する手だてがねえ
こいつの集中力は異常だ
His focus is unbelievable!
Meanwhile, I...
それに比べて 俺は…
Even at this critical moment,
こんなときだってのに—
my head is filled with
everything but the contest!
余計なことばっか
頭をよぎりやがる
Like my life's flashing in front of my eyes.
まるで走馬灯じゃねえか
So many worldly thoughts.
雑念だらけだ
Have I gotten weaker?
俺 弱くなっちまったのかな…
You're not out of it yet!
まだじゃ！
He's right! This is perfect.
（千比路）
そうだ　俺は これでいい
Worldly thoughts or whatever...
雑念でも何でも
全部 抱えたまま 俺は—
I'll shoulder it all and win!
勝つ！
Demon
Demon Wheel!
Wheel
Demon
（荒木）ウワッ！
ウヘヘッ…
最強ーっ！
The strongest!
A present for
your mother!
For Mother's Day!
（蛍）母の日か…
（間宮）いらっしゃいませ
Oh, it's Mother's Day?
Welcome.
ウワッ！
す… すみません！　お店 間違え…
I-I'm sorry! This is the wrong store—
Are you looking for carnations?
（間宮）カーネーションですか？
（蛍）は… はい
Uh, yes...
（蛍）あ〜 びっくりした
いや…　バイトの人かな？
That sure took me by surprise.
Does he work there part-time?
What's his problem?
何だ？　あいつ
Kei-chan, dinner!
（母親）圭ちゃん　ご飯よ！
は〜い
Okay!
They had no way of knowing they would
soon face each other in the sumo ring.
（火ノ丸）のちに
土俵の上で 相まみえようとは—
Mamiya Flower Shop
知る由もない
２人であった
Next Bout      “What's Done is Done"